# **DHANYA PASUPLAN**

## HR Generalist | Employee Relations | Talent Acquisition

@ dpasupalan@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhanya-pasupalan-25077b134

Mavelikkara , Kerala Ph: +91-9961261794

### **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic HR Generalist with 3+ years of experience in HR roles. Proven skills in employee relations, talent acquisition and career guidance. Articulate negotiator skillful in supporting competitive company growth by sourcing top-quality applicants for critical roles. Organized planner with excellent team leadership and program management abilities

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Career Advisor

#### **B-GHUD Academy**

🗰 01/2024 - Present

Mavelikkara, Kerala

- Provided personalized career guidance and counseling to students, primarily nurses, aspiring to work in the UK, New Zealand, Ireland, and other Englishspeaking countries.
- Assisted students in understanding the certification requirements, licensure processes, and visa procedures necessary for employment in their desired destinations.
- Collaborated with recruitment agencies and healthcare institutions in the UK, New Zealand, Ireland, etc., to identify job opportunities for qualified nursing professionals.
- Facilitated the recruitment process by connecting eligible candidates with prospective employers hence improving the success rate to 40 %

#### Recruitment Executive

#### Connectors HR

**m** 08/2022 - 04/2023

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Sourcing candidates from portals like Naukri, LinkedIn, etc and Screening candidates for availability, interest level, and qualifications
- Coordinating with candidates post interview selection for onboarding
- MIS Reports status of joining/requirements assigned.
- Tracked candidates and pushed for feedback on disqualifications, time-to-fill statistics and other variable

## Academic Coordinator

## **B-GHUD Academy**

- Promoted program courses, activities and accomplishments, both internally and externally, to boost recruitment and retain diverse student body.
- Guided and supported faculty and staff in development of new programs
- Tracking Admissions and doing continuous follow ups to ensure client satisfaction

## **HR** Associate

#### White Oval Technologies

- Collaborated with sales and marketing departments to support client acquisition.
- Guided and supported faculty and staff in development of new programs
- Established and maintained highly effective relationships with Employees and industry partners to drive growth.

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Business Administration

#### **Girideepam Business School**

**=** 06/2016 - 08/2018

Kottayam, Kerala

# Bachelor of Technology

# Sri Vellapalli Nateshan College Of Engineering

苗 2012 - 2016 👂 Mavelikkara , Kerala

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Increased Employee Retention**

Implemented employee engagement programs. resulting in a 20% increase in retention rates.



## **Enhanced Onboarding Process**

Streamlined the onboarding process, reducing time-to-productivity by 25% and improving new hire satisfaction.



#### **Successful Talent Acquisition**

Led recruitment efforts, filling all requirements for the role and reducing time-to-fill by 30%.



#### **Developed Career Guidance Policies**

Created and implemented New policies that ensured compliance with employment laws and improved process efficiency.

### **SKILLS**

**Employee Relations** 

**Talent Acquisition** 

**HR Policies** 

**Teamwork** 

**G-Suite** 

**Microsoft Office** 

## **PASSIONS**



#### **Employee Engagement**

Passionate about creating an engaging and inclusive work environment for all employees.



#### **Continuous Learning**

Committed to ongoing professional development and staying updated on HR trends and practices.